A Guide to the Seay family papers, 1835-1986
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Seay family papers, 1835-1986
The Library of Virginia
38805
1.15 cu. ft. and 2 boxes
Seay family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from The History Broker, Roanoke, Virginia.
Biographical Information
George Loving Seay (1804-1874) and his wife Mary Payne Seay (1809-1883) of Fluvanna County, Virginia, had 12 children, one of whom was George Payne Seay (1844-1909). George Payne Seay married Bettie L. Strange (1850-1913) 10 November 1873 and they had a son, George Bledsoe Seay (1881-1964). He married Bessie McFarland (b. 1882) 9 January 1907. They adopted a son, John Bridgeman Seay (1919-2001) in 1935. John B. Seay married Audrey Mae Glass 19 August 1949.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1835-1986, of the Seay family of Fluvanna, Albemarle, and Orange Counties, and Richmond, Virginia, consisting of accounts, cards, certificates, clippings, deeds, drawings, envelopes, financial records, ledgers, letters, manuals, obituaries, poems, promissory notes, ration books, receipts, recipes, songs, stamps, stories, surveys, wills, and other materials mainly of George L. Seay, George P. and Betty Loving Strange Seay, George B. and Bessie M. Seay, John B. and Audrey M. Seay, and John Seay. Collection also contains papers of Joseph Elwood Mitchell of Buckingham County, Virginia, and Winston-Salem, North Carolina.
Contents List
- Papers, 1835-1849 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Papers, 1850-1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Papers, 1868-1869 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Papers, 1883, 1890-1899 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Papers, 1905-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Papers, 1941-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Papers, 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Papers, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Atlantic Life Insurance Company rate tables and agents manual, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Papers, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Car and gas expenses, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Papers, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Papers, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Papers, no date (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Papers (printed materials), no date (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Composition book (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Joseph Elwood Mitchell papers, 1942-1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Envelopes and stamps, 1902, 1906-190[8?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Envelopes and stamps, 1919-1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Envelopes and stamps, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Envelopes and stamps, no year (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Clippings: engagements and marriage, history, obituaries (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Clippings: recipes, soldiers and sailors, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Photograph negatives (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Fluvanna, words by Esther Tutwiler and music by J. W. Tutwiler (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Autumn Reflections by Philip Shumaker (reproduction) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Washington Evening Star death of George V and ascension of Edward VIII, King of England, 21 January 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Washington Herald death of George V and ascension of Edward VIII, King of England, 21 January 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Richmond Afro American extra--end of World War II, 12 May 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Oversize newspaper clippings, 1962, 1973, no date (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The War of 1861-1865 published by the Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Steering Wheel, January 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Col. Grover Criswell's 35th Anniversary Sell-A-Bration, [1981?] (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Dogs Playing Poker by C. M. Coolidge (poster reproductions) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Hotel account book[?], Fluvanna County[?], 1849-1850 (Box 2)
- Account books [Bessie?] Seay family, 1914-1918 (Box 2)
- Seay family account ledger [John B. Seay?], 1961 (Box 2)
- Flowers painted on wood (Box 2)